<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metacommunication | Disruptively sincere]]></title>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/category/metacommunication/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-14T13:16:09+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://disrupts.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[disrupts]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gone Home, an Experience Rather Than a Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/gone-home/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/gone-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Art is about telling a story</em></p>

<p>Any form of art I can thing of right now somehow wishes to tell a story, let it be music, paintings or even photography (this one deserves a whole post).
Even Richard Serra sculptures (I love them by the way) tell stories, and deep ones with yourself as the protagonist.</p>

<p>Why this intro? because video-games are also storytelling devices.
They can also be Art.</p>

<p>I recently played through <a href="http://www.gonehomegame.com/"><em>Gone Home</em></a> and loved it, I enjoyed every part of it.
From the heartwarming love story, the storm sounds, the music to the horror-game-like environment.
It was so good I was almost in tears by the end of it (especially during the-last-gig journal entry).</p>

<p>Yet this is not what I want to talk about today.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2014-04-22-gone-home/gone_home_kiss.jpg" width="700" title="A lovely fan art by fortheloveofpizza" ></p>

<p>The best part of it is that story can&rsquo;t be told effectively in any other form of media.
It could be a lovely short story or novel, or even a film but it would lose most of it&rsquo;s strength.</p>

<p>The real magic of the game is just that. Being a game, letting you be the protagonist. You have the last word about what you should see, read, learn and experience during the game. It doesn&rsquo;t force you through a linear path feeding you the plot &ndash; nor the background information about the characters.</p>

<p>It is your decision if you want to go through the house and dig up the secondary stories.
No one forces you to learn how the relationship between Janice and Terrance is, or Terrance current job issues (and alcohol ones), not even Oscar&rsquo;s deep dark storyline.</p>

<p><a href="http://clockworkworlds.com/post/58411117679/the-transgression-you-can-do-better">Oscar&rsquo;s past</a> (beware of the <strong>spoiler</strong> if you follow this link) is the one that really shines. It is the easiest to miss.
It makes a lot of sense.</p>

<p>Sam&rsquo;s last year is the main plot and thus the only one &ldquo;forced&rdquo; on you (this is not what I meant, you&rsquo;re playing it for that story, I hope you get my point).
Your parents story is more difficult to grasp, yet easy to find. Both live in that house. We can clearly see who fills each room or space of the house and Sam gets the most of it.
Oscar is no longer living but he still is the &ldquo;owner&rdquo; of the basement and the secret passages. His story is also the further away in time.
This concept shines with him: his darker secrets are implicit within the little evidence that remains&hellip;</p>

<p>What do you think about it? Have you played it?</p>

<p>Do you share this point of view about video games? Do you think they can offer alternative ways of communication and storytelling?</p>

<p>By the way, did you also fall for Sam? She is just so cute, and with a very deep voice acting!</p>

<p>There is little more I have to say about it (and so much has already been said), so I’ll give you a few links as a follow up:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://revision3.com/rev3gamesreviews/adams-2013-goty">Adam Sessler’s review</a>, this is how I discovered the game (either that or on some <a href="https://twitter.com/acarboni">Anthony Carboni</a> video; the part on <em>Gone Home</em> is right at the end</li>
<li><a href="http://www.terminally-incoherent.com/blog/2014/02/24/gone-home/">Luke Maciak’s review</a> (I just like his blog.)</li>
<li>another Adam Sessler video, <a href="http://revision3.com/rev3gamespreviews/gone-home-interview">an interview to one of the authors</a></li>
</ul>


<p> <em>The Awesome fan art is by <a href="http://fortheloveofpizza.deviantart.com/">fortheloveofpizza</a>, you can find it <a href="http://fortheloveofpizza.deviantart.com/art/Gone-Home-Kiss-417796613">here</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is a Blog Post Journalism?]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/is-a-blog-post-journalism/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/is-a-blog-post-journalism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Objectivity, Subjectivity or Sincerity</em></p>

<p>As I already told you, I wish to write to you, or even talk to you. Whenever I hear the word journalism I think about newspapers but from today I will also think about this blog.Yes, I believe it is journalism, in the more intimate form it can have.I can’t imagine this as a novel, nor an essay. And this is why I like the possibilities that the web platform offers: you can answer me or ask me different questions through the comments, or even send mail. But what is the goal of written press? I honestly can’t think of anything else other to tell you what is going on around the world.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2012-11-28-is-a-blog-post-journalism/002.jpg" width="500"></p>

<p>With information comes another topic: <em>objectivity</em>.
Objectivity in press, is a goal I will not achieve, but not only because of this way of publishing. From the moment I choose those single words and no others I feel I’m being subjective and this is why I won’t try not to be. I don’t think I will ever be able to erase myself from my writings.</p>

<p>And for this reason I decided to change it for <strong>sincerity</strong>!
I’ll sincere to you and explain my thoughts without willing to convince you.
Only to tell you how I think and see.</p>

<p>I like to see it as the difference between two classic types of advertising (if we can call such a thing “classic”).
They we’re traditionally separated into two categories, informative and persuasive (I won’t count subliminal as a type – being rude it would rather fit into a <del>brainwashing technique</del>). Today the frontier between those two is disappearing as most adds are mixing both strategies. However I like to see my blog an informative add shouting: “this is who I am, like it or not, I won’t judge you”</p>

<p>PD: by the way, I am one of those who think blogs will be the main form of journalism in a few years (leaving press sites at the same position as just another form of publishing); this could be the subject of another post&hellip;</p>

<p><em>Image from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/angelicagaskell/">angelicagaskell</a> under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0.">CC BY</a> license.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes Up Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/what-makes-up-writing/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/what-makes-up-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>The act of telling to the world by means of written words felt oddly wrong to me until quite recently</em></p>

<p>I never thought until last week that i could end up building up a blog, and even less that i would be the one to write the posts.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="/assets/images/2012-11-19-what-makes-up-writing/001.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>Several friends of mine write regularly on personal blogs, some others even tried to build a professional journalist one. One of them involved a least 3 people and had several additional writers posting from time to time. A real enterprise grew behind it.</p>

<p>Despite all of that, writing never caught me, it didn’t appealed to me.</p>

<p>However, a few days from now, from the moment i write this few lines, i suddenly got the feeling i could speak to you: unknown reader from the other side of the network.
It was like i knew expressing those thoughts was somehow useful; though i still don’t know how it will, i trust it is going to happen. And this is why i’ve been thinking about what’s makes a up a blog.</p>

<pre><code>* a web site
* a feed (RSS, Atom…)
* a writer
* some posts
</code></pre>

<p>and the most important thing i wasn’t going to forget: YOU</p>

<pre><code>* some readers
</code></pre>

<p>That’s one the main points of writing, beeing read! And it is why i can only say one more thing to end up this post: ENJOY YOUR READING</p>

<p>PS: try out a feed reader of any kind, it will make will make easier and more enjoyable!</p>

<p><em>Image by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rakka_pl/">rakka_pl</a> under <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0.">CC BY</a> license</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
