<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metacommunication | Disruptively sincere]]></title>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/category/metacommunication/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-11T00:03:44+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://disrupts.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[disrupts]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is a Blog Post Journalism?]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/is-a-blog-post-journalism/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/is-a-blog-post-journalism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Objectivity, Subjectivity or Sincerity</em></p>

<p>As I already told you, I wish to write to you, or even talk to you. Whenever I hear the word journalism I think about newspapers but from today I will also think about this blog.Yes, I believe it is journalism, in the more intimate form it can have.I can’t imagine this as a novel, nor an essay. And this is why I like the possibilities that the web platform offers: you can answer me or ask me different questions through the comments, or even send mail. But what is the goal of written press? I honestly can’t think of anything else other to tell you what is going on around the world.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2012-11-28-is-a-blog-post-journalism/002.jpg" width="500"></p>

<p>With information comes another topic: <em>objectivity</em>.
Objectivity in press, is a goal I will not achieve, but not only because of this way of publishing. From the moment I choose those single words and no others I feel I’m being subjective and this is why I won’t try not to be. I don’t think I will ever be able to erase myself from my writings.</p>

<p>And for this reason I decided to change it for <strong>sincerity</strong>!
I’ll sincere to you and explain my thoughts without willing to convince you.
Only to tell you how I think and see.</p>

<p>I like to see it as the difference between two classic types of advertising (if we can call such a thing “classic”).
They we’re traditionally separated into two categories, informative and persuasive (I won’t count subliminal as a type – being rude it would rather fit into a <del>brainwashing technique</del>). Today the frontier between those two is disappearing as most adds are mixing both strategies. However I like to see my blog an informative add shouting: “this is who I am, like it or not, I won’t judge you”</p>

<p>PD: by the way, I am one of those who think blogs will be the main form of journalism in a few years (leaving press sites at the same position as just another form of publishing); this could be the subject of another post&hellip;</p>

<p><em>Image from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/angelicagaskell/">angelicagaskell</a> under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0.">CC BY</a> license.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes Up Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/what-makes-up-writing/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/what-makes-up-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>The act of telling to the world by means of written words felt oddly wrong to me until quite recently</em></p>

<p>I never thought until last week that i could end up building up a blog, and even less that i would be the one to write the posts.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="/assets/images/2012-11-19-what-makes-up-writing/001.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>Several friends of mine write regularly on personal blogs, some others even tried to build a professional journalist one. One of them involved a least 3 people and had several additional writers posting from time to time. A real enterprise grew behind it.</p>

<p>Despite all of that, writing never caught me, it didn’t appealed to me.</p>

<p>However, a few days from now, from the moment i write this few lines, i suddenly got the feeling i could speak to you: unknown reader from the other side of the network.
It was like i knew expressing those thoughts was somehow useful; though i still don’t know how it will, i trust it is going to happen. And this is why i’ve been thinking about what’s makes a up a blog.</p>

<pre><code>* a web site
* a feed (RSS, Atom…)
* a writer
* some posts
</code></pre>

<p>and the most important thing i wasn’t going to forget: YOU</p>

<pre><code>* some readers
</code></pre>

<p>That’s one the main points of writing, beeing read! And it is why i can only say one more thing to end up this post: ENJOY YOUR READING</p>

<p>PS: try out a feed reader of any kind, it will make will make easier and more enjoyable!</p>

<p><em>Image by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rakka_pl/">rakka_pl</a> under <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0.">CC BY</a> license</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
