<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Disruptively sincere]]></title>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T21:49:13+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://disrupts.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[disrupts]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Pokemon Easter Egg in Android 4.4 Calculator App]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/a-pokemon-easter-egg-in-android-4-dot-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/a-pokemon-easter-egg-in-android-4-dot-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your read right, there is an Easter egg in Android!
And about (old-school) <em>Pokemon</em>!, straight from the nineties.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-05-05-a-pokemon-easter-egg-in-android-4-dot-4/android_easter-egg.jpg" width="800"></p>

<p>The screen-shot is from a Galaxy Nexus running a nightly build of CM-11. I don&rsquo;t know if the Easter-egg comes from Google or the CyanogenMod team.
Now that you know, why not twisting the subject a bit!</p>

<p>You might have recognised the <em>Privacy Guard</em> icon! Yes, the one from <a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.org/">CyanogenMod</a>.
I&rsquo;ve been running the nightly builds on my phone for a year and a half and it really works for me.</p>

<p>This ROM suits my way of <a href="http://disrupts.github.io/go-modal">understanding technology</a>. It is a stripped down version of android (stock android) with granular control and many extra configurations, neat and clean!</p>

<p>Aside from a few <em>hiccups</em> (such as the proximity sensor turning off the screen but not disabling the touch-screen in 4.2 (CM-10.1) for some weeks) it is a great experience and always gratifying when after an update you see the new features pop out!</p>

<p>It is always nice to find an Easter egg in software, reminds me of the time when every single video-game add some hidden (or not so hidden) cheats and we used to get them in magazines! Back in the PlayStation (yes, I&rsquo;m talking about the first one that some will remember as PSX) and early PS2 days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Wallpapers]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/more-wallpapers/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-23T01:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/more-wallpapers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This time Haruhi gets her wallpaper, I don&rsquo;t want her to get mad!</p>

<p>I actually used that image as a background for months, at least six. And if it isn&rsquo;t there now it&rsquo;s because I formatted my laptop&rsquo;s hard-drive and forgot about it!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll probably come back some day.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-23-more-wallpapers/haruhi_wallpaper.jpg" width="800"></p>

<p>You can find the original in a higher resolution at <a href="http://www.pixiv.net/member_illust.php?mode=medium&amp;illust_id=34934983">pixiv.net</a>, and thanks to <a href="http://www.pixiv.net/member.php?id=293432">すぎまさ</a>, the original artist!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gone Home, an Experience Rather Than a Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/gone-home/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/gone-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Art is about telling a story</em></p>

<p>Any form of art I can thing of right now somehow wishes to tell a story, let it be music, paintings or even photography (this one deserves a whole post).
Even Richard Serra sculptures (I love them by the way) tell stories, and deep ones with yourself as the protagonist.</p>

<p>Why this intro? because video-games are also storytelling devices.
They can also be Art.</p>

<p>I recently played through <a href="http://www.gonehomegame.com/"><em>Gone Home</em></a> and loved it, I enjoyed every part of it.
From the heartwarming love story, the storm sounds, the music to the horror-game-like environment.
It was so good I was almost in tears by the end of it (especially during the-last-gig journal entry).</p>

<p>Yet this is not what I want to talk about today.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-22-gone-home/gone_home_kiss.jpg" width="700" title="A lovely fan art by fortheloveofpizza" ></p>

<p>The best part of it is that story can&rsquo;t be told effectively in any other form of media.
It could be a lovely short story or novel, or even a film but it would lose most of it&rsquo;s strength.</p>

<p>The real magic of the game is just that. Being a game, letting you be the protagonist. You have the last word about what you should see, read, learn and experience during the game. It doesn&rsquo;t force you through a linear path feeding you the plot &ndash; nor the background information about the characters.</p>

<p>It is your decision if you want to go through the house and dig up the secondary stories.
No one forces you to learn how the relationship between Janice and Terrance is, or Terrance current job issues (and alcohol ones), not even Oscar&rsquo;s deep dark storyline.</p>

<p><a href="http://clockworkworlds.com/post/58411117679/the-transgression-you-can-do-better">Oscar&rsquo;s past</a> (beware of the <strong>spoiler</strong> if you follow this link) is the one that really shines. It is the easiest to miss.
It makes a lot of sense.</p>

<p>Sam&rsquo;s last year is the main plot and thus the only one &ldquo;forced&rdquo; on you (this is not what I meant, you&rsquo;re playing it for that story, I hope you get my point).
Your parents story is more difficult to grasp, yet easy to find. Both live in that house. We can clearly see who fills each room or space of the house and Sam gets the most of it.
Oscar is no longer living but he still is the &ldquo;owner&rdquo; of the basement and the secret passages. His story is also the further away in time.
This concept shines with him: his darker secrets are implicit within the little evidence that remains&hellip;</p>

<p>What do you think about it? Have you played it?</p>

<p>Do you share this point of view about video games? Do you think they can offer alternative ways of communication and storytelling?</p>

<p>By the way, did you also fall for Sam? She is just so cute, and with a very deep voice acting!</p>

<p>There is little more I have to say about it (and so much has already been said), so I’ll give you a few links as a follow up:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://revision3.com/rev3gamesreviews/adams-2013-goty">Adam Sessler’s review</a>, this is how I discovered the game (either that or on some <a href="https://twitter.com/acarboni">Anthony Carboni</a> video; the part on <em>Gone Home</em> is right at the end</li>
<li><a href="http://www.terminally-incoherent.com/blog/2014/02/24/gone-home/">Luke Maciak’s review</a> (I just like his blog.)</li>
<li>another Adam Sessler video, <a href="http://revision3.com/rev3gamespreviews/gone-home-interview">an interview to one of the authors</a></li>
</ul>


<p> <em>The Awesome fan art is by <a href="http://fortheloveofpizza.deviantart.com/">fortheloveofpizza</a>, you can find it <a href="http://fortheloveofpizza.deviantart.com/art/Gone-Home-Kiss-417796613">here</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anime Wallpaper!]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/anime-wallpaper/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/anime-wallpaper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I never thought I would end up posting wallpapers from someone else when I started the blog. I follow some writers who used to do that and even posted them once a week (such as <a href="http://hfaust.me/">Heinrich Faust</a>).</p>

<p>There will be a difference, I will only post wallpapers I have actually used and keep for a reasonably long period of time! Let&rsquo;s say at least a month (an etternety for wallpapers, once you get into the habit of changing them they tend to last less and less).</p>

<p>This time I&rsquo;ll start with a <a href="http:www.wikipedia.org/kill_la_kill"><em>Kill la Kill</em></a>, as a follow up from the <a href="http://disrupts.github.io/4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante"><em>con</em></a></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-11-anime-wallpaper/satsuki_wallpaper.jpg" width="800"></p>

<p>You can find the original in a higher resolution at <a href="http://www.pixiv.net/member_illust.php?mode=medium&amp;illust_id=42044254">pixiv.net</a>, and thanks to <a href="http://www.pixiv.net/member.php?id=2148690">しょういん</a> who&rsquo;s the original artist!</p>

<p>What do you think? worth of your background? <em>(it is still occupying mine)</em></p>

<p>See you soon</p>

<p><em>I&rsquo;m still figuring out how to include a link in an image to let you click strait to the original.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4º Salón Del Manga De Alicante - a Blast!]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T14:25:29+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend was the 4º <em><a href="http://www.smalicante.com/">Salón del Manga de Alicante</a></em>, an manga/anime/games-centric <em>con</em> at my hometown.
I missed the first three editions, living abroad, and therefore was impatient to go. As you may have guessed from the title, it was incredibly fun.</p>

<p>The day was great, a real catharsis. More so than any film, tv-show or maybe even book I&rsquo;ve enjoyed recently.
I&rsquo;ve got my good-old smile back, and it&rsquo;ll be there for long! &ndash; could be my inner-child taking the wheel this month.</p>

<p>Ok, but what was so enjoyable of it?</p>

<p>Are nice people all over the place to meet, many great costumes and weirder fandoms than yours not enough?
Cause, you know:</p>

<blockquote><p>There&#8217;s always a bigger fish</p><footer><strong>Qui-Gon Jinn</strong> <cite>Star Wars Episode I: The Phantom Menace</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about what happened there (at least what I saw of it, saturday afternoon).</p>

<p>Here are some picks from the cosplay contest!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_1.jpg" width="600">
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_2.jpg" width="400">
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_3.jpg" width="600">
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_4.jpg" width="600"></p>

<p>Competition was harsh, and costumes very elaborate. But please, give me a hand spotting the fandoms!</p>

<p>What if your thing is more video-games? There was also a contest for you.
And even old-school titles that resonate deep in the memories of my generation.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_11.jpg" width="600" title="Tetris contest!" >
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_10.jpg" width="600" title="DDR for the brave" ></p>

<p>There was even a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mario_Kart_64"><em>Mario Kart 64</em></a> contest going on! Arcade racing for everyone.</p>

<p>Many people my age and many more younger teens enjoyed the show, but also entire families sharing their cosplay theme!</p>

<p>I even <em>caught</em> a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mew_%28Pok%C3%A9mon%29">Pokemon</a>! No glitch required &ndash; I hope the younger ones will get that reference, if you don&rsquo;t please ask around, it&rsquo;ll be fun!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_15.jpg" width="600" title="Mew reading *Ghost in the Shell*" ></p>

<p>There even was a concert within the con.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_9.jpg" width="600" title="WhiteNoise playing Aya Hirano's *God Knows*" ></p>

<p>And a good one! Check it out!</p>

<iframe width="770" height="430" src="http://disrupts.github.io//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QQq5lH387js" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>And a small but fully-packed console expo! From a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnavox_Odyssey">Magnavox Odyssey</a> a limited edition <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PSX_%28video_game_console%29">PSX</a> directly from japan!</p>

<p>Before talking about cosplays, let&rsquo;s talk about tea!</p>

<p>I had my first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bubble_tea">bubble tea</a>. Mango! Loved the taste, although bubbles were a little to strong for me. It deffinitly won&rsquo;t the last! Sorry there is no picture, I was too concentrated, enjoying the drink while listening WhiteNoise play.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve already said costumes were great, but I can&rsquo;t say it loud enough! and of every style you can think of.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_5.jpg" width="400" title="A Samurai time-traveler lost at the convention" >
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_6.jpg" width="400" title="Some of the many *Kill la Kill* fans!" >
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_13.jpg" width="600" title="Vocaloid fans! Hurray" >
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_7.jpg" width="600" title="Close-up on *Magnet* headphones and a cute cosplayer" >
<img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_8.jpg" width="600" title="SAO!" ></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m saving the best for the end!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2014-04-08-4o-salon-del-manga-de-alicante-a-blast/manga_alicante_2014_12.jpg" width="650" title="A real-life Satsuki Kiryuin" ></p>

<p>That cosplayer nailed it, the costume is incredible and the pose was so faithful I was shocked.
I hopped to find a Satsuki cosplay, but I had to wait nearly to the end of the day to come across her! &ndash; ok, I might be a little biased towards that character, I won&rsquo;t admit it though.</p>

<p>I even found a few <em>ToG</em> fans! (yes, SIU has me addicted).</p>

<p>To be fair, the conference was dominated by <em>Attack on Titan</em>. It was by far the biggest fan-group.</p>

<p>There were a few martial arts demo too, too bad I had no time for it (As traditional Jiu Jitsu fan, I would have loved the Japanese archery demo).</p>

<p>Wrapping up, don&rsquo;t be ashamed of your fandoms&#8217; there&rsquo;s a reason you like them! (and you&rsquo;re not the only one).</p>

<p><em>All photos are release under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons BY-NC-SA license</a>.</em>
<em>If you want a higher resolution version please contact me via <a href="mailto:disrupts@outlook.com">email</a> (PGP keys on their way).</em>
<em>Props to all those awesome cosplayers, they are the real artists!</em>
<em>And if you recognise yourself in the photos, tell me what you think! I&rsquo;d love to hang out some time!</em>
<em>I also want to thank <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/blackjan86">blackjan86</a>, a good friend of mine for recording and uploading a few videos of the concert!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on WWDC MMXIII]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Ok, some time has passed, I watched the WWDC stream live, and have a mixed opinion about it. Overall I without doubt say I expected more from Apple, something more groundbreaking or risky.</em></p>

<p><strong>I shall start with the bad, otherwise it would be too much to end with.</strong></p>

<p>Mac OS X 10.9 Mavericks brings:</p>

<ul>
<li>tabs in Finder, pretty easy to foresee, but at least they could have done it right (many apps do it on 10.6 to 10.8 such as <a href="http://www.trankynam.com/xtrafinder/">XtraFinder</a> which include several more features including the very useful split pane)</li>
<li>a multiple display upgrade, well that isn’t a new feature, but rather a bug in Mountain Lion when using full screen apps that needed to be removed&hellip;</li>
<li>tagging is new but not a new concept and already available with third party apps such as for tabs</li>
</ul>


<p>and feels like bug tracking more than a real upgrade (and this I’m confident is because they are preparing something bigger for next release).</p>

<p>New Macbook air brings many hardware improvements but no innovation, no tactile screen as there is no new hybrid OS. Apple will be one more year behind Windows 8 and it is going to hurt them if they don’t come up with something really big next because many people will go to Microsoft to get a sense of novelty (many “dockable” Intel-Atom based Windows tablets (or with detachable keyboards) are already getting people’s attention, and those can legitimately replace netbooks as they run the full OS (not the ARM version)).
One great thing of the new Apple Laptops are the 802.11 ac wireless chipsets! That is modern stuff, but that actually didn’t surprise me. It was rather the lack of it in both the Xbox One and Playstation 4 where both are stuck with n. [between you and me, it is ad I can&rsquo;t wait to see!]</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2013-06-12-thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii/007.jpg" width="800" title="iOS 7" ></p>

<p><strong>The good things!</strong></p>

<p>A new Mac Pro (well it was a must, it had been too long since the last update, but at least they are totally fresh models). The shape is weird but according to them it is for cooling purposes (by now, we all know how obsessed they are with fan noise). I didn’t get well the hard disk specs but it seemed like they were going fully flash. It is nice for a production machine but to store the end products spinning hard drives are a must. That will probably be configurable before buying though. The best of them is the 4k support! They really have in mind video and photo editing (all their displays already come nicely calibrated, all of them, from the iPhone to their biggest monitor).</p>

<p>The new Siri voice is just astonishing. Siri has new features, but nothing extraordinary. It just does what everyone expected it to do: it is able to change settings. But those new voices, they are just gorgeous.</p>

<p>The car stuff seems nice. I didn’t get how it is going to work (software-wise) but it will bring better voice control (I imagine it will use mikes already placed inside the car by manufacturers for hands-free systems). I just want to see how deep the integration is and how well they can use the cars’ built in displays.</p>

<p><strong>and now it’s time for the weird things Apple showed us:</strong></p>

<p>iOS 7, I couldn’t call it good or bad. It is a visual redesign and a catch up on specs (as compared to Android 4.2). The Control center, Safari features, multitasking (except for the 4 finger gestures the iPad already has) and the animated backgrounds are nothing new for those on the other side of the fence. As I already mentioned, it seems like a distilled upgrade waiting for something big coming up (the visual change was a necessity, 6 versions alike isn’t good and will help people move to the next one). In mobile Ubuntu touch will soon be a reference to where we are going (for light users at least, phones won’t catch up full fledged desktop anytime soon).</p>

<p>iWork for iCloud, that was a big ‘WTF’ for me. It just remembered me of the web-based LibreOffice, with GoogleDocs as the one to overthrow (it shouldn’t be difficult if Apple is able to bring all iWork features to usable web interface). As for Microsoft… well any of their devices can run a copy of Office, they don’t feel the urge of doing anything web-based that could have a poor user-experience. At least they surprised me with this!</p>

<p>It felt strange that Apple displayed the number of webkit browsers in use, or even silly… as their’s isn’t the most used one. They are also not the only ones to develop it, nor they built it all from scratch (they forked the KDE browser).</p>

<p>I loved the new Apple tv feature, using it as a display instead of mirroring is something I was looking into for some time. It just makes sense to use any set-top box that is not used at that moment as a replacement for wireless HDMI through any WiFI network (but only if the router is in good shape…). I hope Wayland will be able to bring some similar feature to the OpenSource world because the X mess may not be a suited platform to built it.</p>

<p><em>Those were my thoughts, feel free to comment and start a conversation! I’ll be glad too keep talking about the the upcoming tech.</em></p>

<p><em>Image by ©2013 Apple Inc.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Future Is Today! New Tech Released?]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/the-future-is-today-new-tech-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/the-future-is-today-new-tech-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are about to confirm a trend in technology.</p>

<p>Not only a trend, a new way of interacting with computer.</p>

<p>Tomorrow start E3 and today is Apple’s WWDC.</p>

<p>And I expect to see 2 important things:</p>

<ul>
<li> more possibilities in tactile and voice interaction with computers (consoles in E3)</li>
<li> the way Apple tries face the fact that hybrid OS are the future</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2013-06-10-the-future-is-today-new-tech-released/006.jpg" width="500" title="WWDC 2013" ></p>

<p>The first one I believe is more to see in long term, with Google Glass which change the concept of computers. That computer is no longer for content creation (like any modern desktop or laptop) nor for content consumption (tablets and smartphones). It is designed to receive and display notifications.
That is it’s first goal, but not the only one. Those computerised googles are a new vector for augmented reality.</p>

<p>The second is yet to be seen. Microsoft and Canonical have bet on hybrid software. A software that runs on different architectures and of very different machines (from smartphones to desktops, with tablets and ultra-books  as their target) with the same user experience and even share apps with the older desktop only (i386, amd64, ppc or other) OS.
Apple has yet to show something similar, and it will, but maybe not tomorrow. Many new tablets have arrived from different manufacturers with Windows 8, even some with Intel Atom processors and removable keyboards (giving them the potential to be used as tablets and netbooks). Apple still has two distinct pieces of software (IOS and Mac OS X) that run on totally different hardware (ARM and amd64). The problem it faces is that it is a hardware manufacturers and no other hardware is allowed to be released with their software (with the exception of a laptop for designers that had a Wacom tactile screen and ran Snow Leopard).</p>

<p>Will we see a change in computer architecture for Apple hardware tomorrow (for computers and tablets alike)? or will they move their IPad to Intel hardware? They could also choose to wait 6 more months to release a very polished user experience.</p>

<p>We will see at 10:00 AM Pacific!</p>

<p>PS: The conference is over, now it is time let you know <a href="http://disrupts.github.io/blog/thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii/">what I think about it</a></p>

<p><em>Image by ©2013 Apple Inc.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Access Memories and Nonsensical Metada]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/random-access-memories-and-nonsensical-metada/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T12:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/random-access-memories-and-nonsensical-metada</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve just lost<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> a full post.
yeap, just finished writing it in gvim, hadn’t saved it nor copied it to wordpress online editor and saw miself forced to reboot my computer because.. I ran out of RAM.  I couldn’t switch programs, nor input anything. It was frozen. And it had plenty of space to use for swap (Mac OS X uses a swap file by default) but somehow it couldn’t handle it.</p>

<p>So what was it about?</p>

<p>Some weirdness I was confronted after ripping the new Daft Punk CD (I couldn’t resist, I bought it the same 21st of May it was launched).</p>

<p>The problem came from some alac rips (it did not happened with flac).</p>

<p>The files showed some strange creation dates when opened with <a href="https://mplayerhq.hu/design7/news.html">MPlayer</a>. Some ordered dates starting in the 20′s and ending in the 80′s.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2013-05-25-random-access-memories-and-nonsensical-metada/005.jpg" width="600" title="MPlayer screenshot including some strange metadata" ></p>

<p>At first I though it was some easter egg but after ripping the files a second time I realised those new files showed some similar dates, but not the same. That’s why I blamed XLD (the program I used to transcode from aiff to alac) but that was another mistake. XLD did a great job in finding metadata in a few seconds and ripping the whole album in under 5 min. I ended up blaming MPlayer, because no other player showed that metadata. THey all showed only ’2013′ as the date (which was also showed in a different line by MPlayer, as shown in the screenshot). Even the OS showed a real creation date which is, as expected, the day the files were created by XLD.</p>

<p>What do you think makes MPlayer show those dates consistently every time I play the songs?</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>sorry Apple, your Darwin kernel behaved properly. It was Firefox (from my beloved <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla</a>) which was responsible for the soft-crash. I have it setup to ask me if I want to accept cookies on every new website I visit and somehow one of them broke the app (oddly enough, I was, for once, running the release channel Firefox (stable) instead of <a href="http://nightly.mozilla.org/">Nightly</a> (daily build). That won’t change my mind about the browser and might soon sign up to collaborate with the developers (I came back to Firefox, after having switched to chrome almost at its debut, for <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mission/">philosophical</a> reasons, 2 years ago).<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Modal, Go Simple (& Fast)]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/go-modal/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/go-modal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>From confronting VI to a simplified computer life – or how drastically my usage of computers has changed in little over a year</em></p>

<p>I’ve never considered myself a tweaker or tinkerer, speaking about computers. Sure, I like to configure things to my liking and go through all the settings but not often for visual enhancements. However, time has proven me wrong. As you we’ll see farther down, I ended up changing and configuring most things configurablein an OS, almost from scratch but not for the reasons I suspected.</p>

<p><em>How it all started: the Vim love story</em></p>

<p>A year ago, I found myself looking for a good, a real text editor. I was bored of xcode (hadalready given up visual studio built-in editor) and wanted an opensource alternative, and a multi-purpose one (one to write everything from). And only 2 came to my mind! the BIG ones:</p>

<ul>
<li>Emacs</li>
<li>Vim</li>
</ul>


<p>And thus, I fired up a terminal emulator and gave them a try (both come preinstalled in Mac OS X). 10 min each, the real basics, nothing more: how to write, save and exit a text file.</p>

<p>Emacs looked nice, coming from Richard M. Stallman I wasn’t expecting less (I should say felt, because the looks of a console-based text editor is generally nothing more than the text you are editing), but it was that oldy thing called bI that blew my mind with modes! I got caught by that simplicity which lies beneath the modal design; the fact that you talk to a text editor with verbs and nouns (mandates and objects). Despite “VI VI VI being the editor of the devil” I felt desperately attracted to it.</p>

<p>Since then, Vim has replaced nano as my de facto console editor for small config-files editions and textedit to write simple txt files (’cause yes, I write my to-do lists in txt (their just so easy to share, via sftp, rsync (over ssh for the cypher-enthusiasts), git or so many more) and even some large texts I keep to myself (or not so much as the introduction to an interactive shell I wrote for some friends at university, that i’ll probably publish, though it is more a collection of commands than a real tutorial)) – because I dislike Microsoft word and open office seems over-kill (and it drives resources away from what monopolises my computer: firefox (or should I say “oh how much I hate you” flash)) – when no printing is required (ok, i’ll probably end up writing latex xml from vim and output it to pdf to print docs! but I just haven’t found the right time to start learning it).</p>

<p>I should always remember that before that I had already encountered VI (yes, VI and not vim) while configuring some installs, when it was the only accessible editor (maybe nano too). I was lost back then, I barely knew how to enter interactive mode and always ditched it in favour of nano!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2013-05-25-go-modal/004.jpg" width="700" title="A gVim screenshot (MacVim) of this same post being edited" ></p>

<p>Back to the topic (sorry for that helly amount of digressions, caused by writing directly my thoughts instead of planning the post – which I always intend to do except when I feel I need to get something out (to you and out of my mind) as quick as possible). Vim now drives my computing! I fell in love with its simple design (vi’s but today vim is just the editor hat follows it).
I don’t only mean going modal as much as I can (I <del>should</del> need to try vim zsh/bash modes and vimperator-like plug-ins for everything – firefox, but I also want one for RSSOwl, and Thunderbird if it was my mail client) but the fact that a good use of Vim forces you to stop from time to time to look back at what actions you are doing inefficiently (the ones I get bored, repeating over and over) and write (or catch) plug-ins to replace them.</p>

<p><em>The time where I see repetitions in every task I do</em></p>

<p><em><span style="color:#808080;">Get rid of GUI annoyances</span></em></p>

<p>All of this is why I moved from using the gui to open an app (menus and icons), to using spotlight,dash,or any text driven launcher, to key combinations! I don’t mean launchers aren’t needed, just that for the 10-15 most used apps I’d rather have key-combinations than: 1.”launching the launcher” 2.typing the app first letters and 3.pressing enter. For more rarely used apps the launcher is great.</p>

<p>Using a gui to look up apps I use even less, that I shouldn’t do; if I open the app that rarely it probably means I don’t need that app and thus shouldn’t even be installed!</p>

<p>The same goes for window management! a full fledged gui is great (i’m a huge KDE fan!) but resizing windows is a very tiring task. I first looked for key-combos to switch between commonly used sizes (full screen, halves, quarters) and ended up shift-it and then spectacles on mac os x (spectacles is just the way to go for that, easier to install and configure, with just the desired options).</p>

<p>That was great… until I wanted to resize the windows to different proportions. It still required to use the mouse and waste and awful lot of time. And now you already know (for those who use them) where I was headed! directly into the awesomeness (don’t get me wrong, awesome wm is not the one I chose – haven’t tried that one) of tiling wms! (Xmonad and dwm are the ones that cought my eye, for their simplicity – in their design)).</p>

<p>I still love KDE, and use it on the desktop (don’t really use it often yet, cause it is slow, slower than my everyday, almost 3 years old laptop – that I will probably rock for way longer if I switch to an SSD and upgrade RAM and OS – i’ll move to an everyday linux install (would go freebsd or even openbsd (which I know almost nothing about it) but wireless drivers forbid me to do so). I would use KDE even more if I could get Xmonad or dwm to run on top of it, like the ‘blu-something’ project that I think got merged back with Xmonad that ran on top of gnome2; right that’s a few years old, cause gnome2… ok, not that crazy old, the latter still is in Debian stable repos!</p>

<p><em><span style="color:#808080;">Automate, automate, and keep automating</span></em></p>

<p>Next step in simplifying every day computing scared me at first: scripting to “automate” (not thinking of cron jobs here, just shell scripts, but that is the following step I haven’t reached yet) every-day tasks</p>

<p>The first one that I decided to do is to toggle wifI (and easily as a consequence of it, ethernet) connection.</p>

<p>This is the easiest way I thought to achieve that goal (understand <code>en1</code> or <code>wlan0</code> depending on your platform or should I rather say kernel – because kfreebsd Debian or Gentoo have a special place in my heart – though I feel they’ll end up each in a separate jail, ruled by freebsd :P) :</p>

<pre><code>#! bin/sh
if [ -n echo $(ifconfig en1 | grep inactive -o) ]
then
    ifconfig en1 down
else
    ifconfig en1 up
fi
</code></pre>

<p>But this has a problem: it requires root privileges and i’m not really into running as root 24/7. So these scripts are left for my Kali linux vm (now than we can tweak my Bactrack without having to care about repeating everything with every R iteration – I hope ‘aptitude dist-upgrade’ will work without breaking anything when times come). I tried to chown the script to root and chmod 711 (the latter for security purposes… I don’t want any one being able to modify a script to be run by root) but as many of you probably already know, this doesn’t work either.</p>

<p>Two workarounds comes to my mind (although I haven’t tried any), toggling kernel modules instead of putting the interface down (would be wl module for me… the Broadcom one that drive nuts and forbids me to jump straight into FreeBSD with Debian and Gentoo jails to play all day long with the software repos). The alternative would be to build a root job that waits for a file to change or any other input allowed to normal users. That root script would then toggle the WifI interface. The kernel module solution has a big advantage, it can be used for so many different things that are not stoppable otherwise: RS323, keyboard backlight? (maybe not that one as it comes with special keys, screen backlight and some more utilities…) cd/dvd player to reduce battery consumption…</p>

<p>Of course, the objective of any of those type of scripts is to be run with a key-combination (maybe Control-Super-W for Wifi), or at least an alias (for the ones not used so often or dangerous ones).</p>

<p>Talking danger now. Some tasks should remain painful to prevent a bigger damage (please don’t get me wrong, i’m talking computers only here). Here’s an example.</p>

<p>I don’t know the way you use to shutdown (gui doesn’t count, we’re in a light window manager set-up now (ideally a tiling one) not a desktop environment),
I like: <code>sudo shutdown -h now</code> (I use this command for 2 reasons, I can’t bother remembering halt or poweroff (even if I already know them) because you can do so much more with shutdown! such as adding some delay by changing ‘now’ to ‘+10′ for 10 min, or going to sleep or rebooting instead of halting with <code>-s</code> and <code>-r</code> respectively; and I (you may call be what ever you want for that as long as it is stupid, for that) don’t really know the difference between halting and poweroffing (I imagine shutdown does halting the good way because it is multipurpose, although I could be wrong)).
You got my way of thinking, <code>sudo shutdown -h now</code>  this is too long to type. But even if I shut down my computer daily (I do it weekly… sometimes) assigning a key combo is too dangerous for me. I don’t want to risk turning off the computer because I mistyped some capital letter.</p>

<p>In this case, I give aliases some love. I could use, ‘bye’, ‘byebye’, ‘goodnight’ or even ‘sleepwell’ (though I think those too feel nicer for -s version).</p>

<p><em><span style="color:#808080;"><i>Some repetitive tasks that play better with aliases than keyboard shortcuts</i></span></em></p>

<p>An obvious one: updating your machine. Running:</p>

<pre><code># sudo aptitude update
# sudo aptitude safeupgrade
</code></pre>

<p>for those running debian or descendants (apt-get is a good way to do this too, just don’t come near me with a <code>yum update</code> – just joking, nothing against you Fedora, Red Hat, Mandrake, Mandriva guys – maybe it’s just envy I feel)</p>

<pre><code># emerge --sync
# emerge --update --ask world
</code></pre>

<p>both ways are too long and soon get boring. A simple alias and all of this is done in a breeze (maybe: <code>rotfl</code> or <code>updateyourselgdumbass</code> (ok, maybe not, that’s again too long, I don’t want to end up aliasing that for something else, though that would be funny especially with friends that tend to shouldersurf too much) or ‘uptodate)</p>

<p><em><span style="color:#808080;"><i>A last one for pleasure</i></span></em></p>

<p>This is the last key-combo (because it deserves one,(and an aliases for some options too)) and I haven’t written it yet (but I know it is easily doable).</p>

<p>To get you in perspective, imagine yourself in a freshly cooked linux box, (still no gui, frame-buffer only or a light window manager). what is the most shocking thing you face when you just landed there from a desktop environment? there is no automated mounting of inserted drives (I don’t discriminate between usb flash-drives, SD or other cards or even hard-drives with usb-enclosures nor between file systems; which one do you like? still old and maybe not that classy fat, NTFS, hfs(+), any ext flavour or some good looking weirdos (at least in this situation – haven’t found a single external drive in any of those file systems) such as ZFS or Btrfs?)</p>

<p>So what should we do ? (I’m going through this right now :&ndash;( ). Write a script to auto-mount a fat drive in a given usb port (maybe it will work recursively for all ports, won’t know until I try to write it) and launch it with an alias. Then what if your drive is not fat? add with a few simple arguments to that script! <code>mountme hfs</code> or <code>mountme ntfs</code>. If you, like me and don’t know enough sh scripting to use arguments (or for simplicity), just create separate scripts and substitute the white space with an underscore <code>mountme_zfs</code> or just remove it <code>mountmeext4</code>.</p>

<p>Starting with these seems like good idea, you’ll have time later on to figure which ones you use the most and add shortcuts.</p>

<p>If we end up needing to specify the usb port it won’t be much more difficult: <code>mountme1fat</code> (I would use mountmeX for fat as it is still the most common… :-S or for exfat if you have switched already your flash-drives to that one). the same goes for keyboard shortcuts, adding a 1 or a 2 to a shortcut is a bit painful but I think it is worth not having to type even a short command.</p>

<p><em>and this was, and still is (will always be, because more things can be simplified), my way to laziness!</em></p>

<p><em>It requires a lot a work at first and some commitment but it is very quickly rewarding, so much more when you come back to your computer after a trip to a default gui (such as a university windows box, or a friends’, or a family KDE/gnome/unity box that needed local or remote maintenance (remote is the worse, so painful… especially with a low upload-speed connection)).
At least I don’t have go through this again! I just need to keep my dot-files in a safe place forever… (this sentence reads code control ;&ndash;) )</em></p>

<p>PS: as you might have guessed, Debian is my way to go when I feel lazy on linux and need a rock solid packet manager (haven’t lived enough on rpm side of life, except a few weeks to manage my mother’s laptop until I reinstalled an Ubuntu LTS on it because I couldn’t go along with Meego –mainly for the lack of support, ok, maybe I also thought that atom chip could fly a bit higher, even with unity); and I turn to gentoo when I wan’t to all crazy about source (haven’t tried any sorcerer descended distro, (either lunar, which feels a farther descent because it looks more machiny and not so much fairy) with their (I must say it kinda attracts me a little beside sounding a bit foolish) magic casting way to compile. haven’t tried CRUX despite liking the whole idea behind it –remember my affinity to Beasty– though I like so much Gentoo’s USEFLAGS I don’t feel I will ever try to jump to CRUX, not even for a 2 day trial– who knows). Between Gentoo and Funtoo, can’t say. I should try them both for longer but for now I can keep rsync for a while (git is good too, but hey, not yet worth switching).</p>

<p>PS 2: I hope my writing was funny enough (maybe it isn’t at all, and i’m all wrong about my way of blogging) to keep you reading till the end! congratulations if you did! you deserve a price, but I don’t have enough energy reaming to think about one.</p>

<p>PS 3: I just realised I never mentioned how to make key-combos for scripts, but this you will naturally discover while configuring a tiling wm and every one is different. for dwm and Xmonad it comes down to editing the header file and recompiling the binary (sounds awful at first but you can do it with a keyboard shortcut by default in the last releases of Xmonad – or maybe you just don’t need to recompile everything any more, I sincerely don’t remember). In Mac OS X, use Automator services to start shell scripts with a keyboard shortcut that you can assign later from the keyboard configuration panel.</p>

<p><em>yes, this is slightly meant to be an ever alive-post, making inserts with new tricks and whistles when I come across them.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2014 F1]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/the-2014-f1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T12:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/the-2014-f1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>UPDATE 2014</em></strong>: <em>FIA made a different decision, F1 cars now use turbo-charged V6 1.6l engines.</em></p>

<p><em>What can f1 turn to be with the smallest engines in decades, a 1.6l, 4 cilinder turbocharged gasoline heart</em></p>

<p>The FIA is still deciding the F1 rules for next year; so don’t blame me if 2014 rules change from the ones proposed some time ago, they’re just that a proposition to be negociated and confirmed.</p>

<p>The biggest change it would bring to the cars is none other than the engine. Instead of the 2.4l V8 NA engines of today — limited at 18 000 rpm — (or the 3.0l V10 before 2009), we will see inline 4 cylinder 1.6l engines limited at 12 000 rpm (and this part has already been confirmed). The good news to keep up with track times (well, not be horribly slower from one year to another) is turbochargers are legal again!</p>

<p>What does that mean to us? whatching F1 from the outside. Well, a lot more than we might initially think.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2012-11-28-the-2014-f1/003.jpg" width="700" title="F1 - YasMarinaCirtuit 2010" ></p>

<p>First of all it makes it a lot more difficult for drivers to control cars, especially the lower end ones. Turbos mean turbo lag is back! A nightmare for unexperienced drivers. But of today’s pilots how many have driven turbo-charged cars before? not many. Most of them come from karting, gp2 and gp3. Good drivers could reveal themselves and show off their real skills.
It also means more pressure inside the engine. And the new 1.6l engines will be lighter and weaker than your average car engine of the same size. Aggresive drivers should take care of not overrevving the new motors because it could turn to be decisive for the championship.</p>

<p>New engines also means new opportunities. What about kers driven electric compressors (such as the one Mazda is likely to incorporate in they’re new car, a new version of their rotary engine powerred sports car (the rx7) that could be designated as rx9)! It could work as an electric antilag system to make the kers button usable under 80km/h or as a presure boost for high revs (this would be very helpful if small turbos are used, which would reduce lag and make cars more predictable and easier to drive).</p>

<p>Those compressors (the electric ones) bring back a problem: a rule forbids engines which  do not move directly the wheels, propelling the car (the rule was created to prevent vacuum engines under the cars used to generate high downforce even at low speed tight corners)</p>

<p>I will keep you up to date with this, if I get a chance to read those rules I try to figure out if those electric compressors would be legal; but again, rules might change until 2014.</p>

<p><em>Image by <a href="https://secure.flickr.com/photos/jiteshjagadish">jiteshjagadish</a> under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0">CC BY</a> license</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is a Blog Post Journalism?]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/is-a-blog-post-journalism/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/is-a-blog-post-journalism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Objectivity, Subjectivity or Sincerity</em></p>

<p>As I already told you, I wish to write to you, or even talk to you. Whenever I hear the word journalism I think about newspapers but from today I will also think about this blog.Yes, I believe it is journalism, in the more intimate form it can have.I can’t imagine this as a novel, nor an essay. And this is why I like the possibilities that the web platform offers: you can answer me or ask me different questions through the comments, or even send mail. But what is the goal of written press? I honestly can’t think of anything else other to tell you what is going on around the world.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2012-11-28-is-a-blog-post-journalism/002.jpg" width="500"></p>

<p>With information comes another topic: <em>objectivity</em>.
Objectivity in press, is a goal I will not achieve, but not only because of this way of publishing. From the moment I choose those single words and no others I feel I’m being subjective and this is why I won’t try not to be. I don’t think I will ever be able to erase myself from my writings.</p>

<p>And for this reason I decided to change it for <strong>sincerity</strong>!
I’ll sincere to you and explain my thoughts without willing to convince you.
Only to tell you how I think and see.</p>

<p>I like to see it as the difference between two classic types of advertising (if we can call such a thing “classic”).
They we’re traditionally separated into two categories, informative and persuasive (I won’t count subliminal as a type – being rude it would rather fit into a <del>brainwashing technique</del>). Today the frontier between those two is disappearing as most adds are mixing both strategies. However I like to see my blog an informative add shouting: “this is who I am, like it or not, I won’t judge you”</p>

<p>PD: by the way, I am one of those who think blogs will be the main form of journalism in a few years (leaving press sites at the same position as just another form of publishing); this could be the subject of another post&hellip;</p>

<p><em>Image from <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/angelicagaskell/">angelicagaskell</a> under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0.">CC BY</a> license.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes Up Writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/what-makes-up-writing/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T12:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/what-makes-up-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>The act of telling to the world by means of written words felt oddly wrong to me until quite recently</em></p>

<p>I never thought until last week that i could end up building up a blog, and even less that i would be the one to write the posts.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://disrupts.github.io/assets/images/2012-11-19-what-makes-up-writing/001.jpg" width="300"></p>

<p>Several friends of mine write regularly on personal blogs, some others even tried to build a professional journalist one. One of them involved a least 3 people and had several additional writers posting from time to time. A real enterprise grew behind it.</p>

<p>Despite all of that, writing never caught me, it didn’t appealed to me.</p>

<p>However, a few days from now, from the moment i write this few lines, i suddenly got the feeling i could speak to you: unknown reader from the other side of the network.
It was like i knew expressing those thoughts was somehow useful; though i still don’t know how it will, i trust it is going to happen. And this is why i’ve been thinking about what’s makes a up a blog.</p>

<pre><code>* a web site
* a feed (RSS, Atom…)
* a writer
* some posts
</code></pre>

<p>and the most important thing i wasn’t going to forget: YOU</p>

<pre><code>* some readers
</code></pre>

<p>That’s one the main points of writing, beeing read! And it is why i can only say one more thing to end up this post: ENJOY YOUR READING</p>

<p>PS: try out a feed reader of any kind, it will make will make easier and more enjoyable!</p>

<p><em>Image by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rakka_pl/">rakka_pl</a> under <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0.">CC BY</a> license</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
