<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Software | Disruptively sincere]]></title>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/category/software/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T13:04:36+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://disrupts.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[disrupts]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Pokemon Easter Egg in Android 4.4 Calculator App]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/a-pokemon-easter-egg-in-android-4-dot-4/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/a-pokemon-easter-egg-in-android-4-dot-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your read right, there is an Easter egg in Android!
And about (old-school) <em>Pokemon</em>!, straight from the nineties.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2014-05-05-a-pokemon-easter-egg-in-android-4-dot-4/android_easter-egg.jpg" width="800"></p>

<p>Now that you know, why not twisting the subject a bit!</p>

<p>You might have recognised the <em>Privacy Guard</em> icon! Yes, the one from <a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.org/">CyanogenMod</a>.
I&rsquo;ve been running the nightly builds on my phone for a year and a half and it really works for me.</p>

<p>This ROM suits my way of <a href="/go-modal">understanding technology</a>. It is a stripped down version of android (stock android) with granular control and many extra configurations, neat and clean!</p>

<p>Aside from a few <em>hiccups</em> (such as the proximity sensor turning off the screen but not disabling the touch-screen in 4.2 (CM10.1) for some weeks) it is a great experience and always gratifying when after an update you see the new features pop out!</p>

<p>It is always nice to find an Easter egg in software, reminds me of the time when every single video-game add some hidden (or not so hidden) cheats and we used to get them in magazines! Back in the PlayStation (yes, I&rsquo;m talking about the first one that some will remember as PSX) and early PS2 days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gone Home, an Experience Rather Than a Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/gone-home/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/gone-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Art is about telling a story</em></p>

<p>Any form of art I can thing of right now somehow wishes to tell a story, let it be music, paintings or even photography (this one deserves a whole post).
Even Richard Serra sculptures (I love them by the way) tell stories, and deep ones with yourself as the protagonist.</p>

<p>Why this intro? because video-games are also storytelling devices.
They can also be Art.</p>

<p>I recently played through <a href="http://www.gonehomegame.com/"><em>Gone Home</em></a> and loved it, I enjoyed every part of it.
From the heartwarming love story, the storm sounds, the music to the horror-game-like environment.
It was so good I was almost in tears by the end of it (especially during the-last-gig journal entry).</p>

<p>Yet this is not what I want to talk about today.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2014-04-22-gone-home/gone_home_kiss.jpg" width="700" title="A lovely fan art by fortheloveofpizza" ></p>

<p>The best part of it is that story can&rsquo;t be told effectively in any other form of media.
It could be a lovely short story or novel, or even a film but it would lose most of it&rsquo;s strength.</p>

<p>The real magic of the game is just that. Being a game, letting you be the protagonist. You have the last word about what you should see, read, learn and experience during the game. It doesn&rsquo;t force you through a linear path feeding you the plot &ndash; nor the background information about the characters.</p>

<p>It is your decision if you want to go through the house and dig up the secondary stories.
No one forces you to learn how the relationship between Janice and Terrance is, or Terrance current job issues (and alcohol ones), not even Oscar&rsquo;s deep dark storyline.</p>

<p><a href="http://clockworkworlds.com/post/58411117679/the-transgression-you-can-do-better">Oscar&rsquo;s past</a> (beware of the <strong>spoiler</strong> if you follow this link) is the one that really shines. It is the easiest to miss.
It makes a lot of sense.</p>

<p>Sam&rsquo;s last year is the main plot and thus the only one &ldquo;forced&rdquo; on you (this is not what I meant, you&rsquo;re playing it for that story, I hope you get my point).
Your parents story is more difficult to grasp, yet easy to find. Both live in that house. We can clearly see who fills each room or space of the house and Sam gets the most of it.
Oscar is no longer living but he still is the &ldquo;owner&rdquo; of the basement and the secret passages. His story is also the further away in time.
This concept shines with him: his darker secrets are implicit within the little evidence that remains&hellip;</p>

<p>What do you think about it? Have you played it?</p>

<p>Do you share this point of view about video games? Do you think they can offer alternative ways of communication and storytelling?</p>

<p>By the way, did you also fall for Sam? She is just so cute, and with a very deep voice acting!</p>

<p>There is little more I have to say about it (and so much has already been said), so I’ll give you a few links as a follow up:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://revision3.com/rev3gamesreviews/adams-2013-goty">Adam Sessler’s review</a>, this is how I discovered the game (either that or on some <a href="https://twitter.com/acarboni">Anthony Carboni</a> video; the part on <em>Gone Home</em> is right at the end</li>
<li><a href="http://www.terminally-incoherent.com/blog/2014/02/24/gone-home/">Luke Maciak’s review</a> (I just like his blog.)</li>
<li>another Adam Sessler video, <a href="http://revision3.com/rev3gamespreviews/gone-home-interview">an interview to one of the authors</a></li>
</ul>


<p> <em>The Awesome fan art is by <a href="http://fortheloveofpizza.deviantart.com/">fortheloveofpizza</a>, you can find it <a href="http://fortheloveofpizza.deviantart.com/art/Gone-Home-Kiss-417796613">here</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on WWDC MMXIII]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-12T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Ok, some time has passed, I watched the WWDC stream live, and have a mixed opinion about it. Overall I without doubt say I expected more from Apple, something more groundbreaking or risky.</em></p>

<p><strong>I shall start with the bad, otherwise it would be too much to end with.</strong></p>

<p>Mac OS X 10.9 Mavericks brings:</p>

<ul>
<li>tabs in Finder, pretty easy to foresee, but at least they could have done it right (many apps do it on 10.6 to 10.8 such as <a href="http://www.trankynam.com/xtrafinder/">XtraFinder</a> which include several more features including the very useful split pane)</li>
<li>a multiple display upgrade, well that isn’t a new feature, but rather a bug in Mountain Lion when using full screen apps that needed to be removed&hellip;</li>
<li>tagging is new but not a new concept and already available with third party apps such as for tabs</li>
</ul>


<p>and feels like bug tracking more than a real upgrade (and this I’m confident is because they are preparing something bigger for next release).</p>

<p>New Macbook air brings many hardware improvements but no innovation, no tactile screen as there is no new hybrid OS. Apple will be one more year behind Windows 8 and it is going to hurt them if they don’t come up with something really big next because many people will go to Microsoft to get a sense of novelty (many “dockable” Intel-Atom based Windows tablets (or with detachable keyboards) are already getting people’s attention, and those can legitimately replace netbooks as they run the full OS (not the ARM version)).
One great thing of the new Apple Laptops are the 802.11 ac wireless chipsets! That is modern stuff, but that actually didn’t surprise me. It was rather the lack of it in both the Xbox One and Playstation 4 where both are stuck with n. [between you and me, it is ad I can&rsquo;t wait to see!]</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2013-06-12-thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii/007.jpg" width="800" title="iOS 7" ></p>

<p><strong>The good things!</strong></p>

<p>A new Mac Pro (well it was a must, it had been too long since the last update, but at least they are totally fresh models). The shape is weird but according to them it is for cooling purposes (by now, we all know how obsessed they are with fan noise). I didn’t get well the hard disk specs but it seemed like they were going fully flash. It is nice for a production machine but to store the end products spinning hard drives are a must. That will probably be configurable before buying though. The best of them is the 4k support! They really have in mind video and photo editing (all their displays already come nicely calibrated, all of them, from the iPhone to their biggest monitor).</p>

<p>The new Siri voice is just astonishing. Siri has new features, but nothing extraordinary. It just does what everyone expected it to do: it is able to change settings. But those new voices, they are just gorgeous.</p>

<p>The car stuff seems nice. I didn’t get how it is going to work (software-wise) but it will bring better voice control (I imagine it will use mikes already placed inside the car by manufacturers for hands-free systems). I just want to see how deep the integration is and how well they can use the cars’ built in displays.</p>

<p><strong>and now it’s time for the weird things Apple showed us:</strong></p>

<p>iOS 7, I couldn’t call it good or bad. It is a visual redesign and a catch up on specs (as compared to Android 4.2). The Control center, Safari features, multitasking (except for the 4 finger gestures the iPad already has) and the animated backgrounds are nothing new for those on the other side of the fence. As I already mentioned, it seems like a distilled upgrade waiting for something big coming up (the visual change was a necessity, 6 versions alike isn’t good and will help people move to the next one). In mobile Ubuntu touch will soon be a reference to where we are going (for light users at least, phones won’t catch up full fledged desktop anytime soon).</p>

<p>iWork for iCloud, that was a big ‘WTF’ for me. It just remembered me of the web-based LibreOffice, with GoogleDocs as the one to overthrow (it shouldn’t be difficult if Apple is able to bring all iWork features to usable web interface). As for Microsoft… well any of their devices can run a copy of Office, they don’t feel the urge of doing anything web-based that could have a poor user-experience. At least they surprised me with this!</p>

<p>It felt strange that Apple displayed the number of webkit browsers in use, or even silly… as their’s isn’t the most used one. They are also not the only ones to develop it, nor they built it all from scratch (they forked the KDE browser).</p>

<p>I loved the new Apple tv feature, using it as a display instead of mirroring is something I was looking into for some time. It just makes sense to use any set-top box that is not used at that moment as a replacement for wireless HDMI through any WiFI network (but only if the router is in good shape…). I hope Wayland will be able to bring some similar feature to the OpenSource world because the X mess may not be a suited platform to built it.</p>

<p><em>Those were my thoughts, feel free to comment and start a conversation! I’ll be glad too keep talking about the the upcoming tech.</em></p>

<p><em>Image by ©2013 Apple Inc.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Future Is Today! New Tech Released?]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/the-future-is-today-new-tech-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/the-future-is-today-new-tech-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are about to confirm a trend in technology.</p>

<p>Not only a trend, a new way of interacting with computer.</p>

<p>Tomorrow start E3 and today is Apple’s WWDC.</p>

<p>And I expect to see 2 important things:</p>

<ul>
<li> more possibilities in tactile and voice interaction with computers (consoles in E3)</li>
<li> the way Apple tries face the fact that hybrid OS are the future</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2013-06-10-the-future-is-today-new-tech-released/006.jpg" width="500" title="WWDC 2013" ></p>

<p>The first one I believe is more to see in long term, with Google Glass which change the concept of computers. That computer is no longer for content creation (like any modern desktop or laptop) nor for content consumption (tablets and smartphones). It is designed to receive and display notifications.
That is it’s first goal, but not the only one. Those computerised googles are a new vector for augmented reality.</p>

<p>The second is yet to be seen. Microsoft and Canonical have bet on hybrid software. A software that runs on different architectures and of very different machines (from smartphones to desktops, with tablets and ultra-books  as their target) with the same user experience and even share apps with the older desktop only (i386, amd64, ppc or other) OS.
Apple has yet to show something similar, and it will, but maybe not tomorrow. Many new tablets have arrived from different manufacturers with Windows 8, even some with Intel Atom processors and removable keyboards (giving them the potential to be used as tablets and netbooks). Apple still has two distinct pieces of software (IOS and Mac OS X) that run on totally different hardware (ARM and amd64). The problem it faces is that it is a hardware manufacturers and no other hardware is allowed to be released with their software (with the exception of a laptop for designers that had a Wacom tactile screen and ran Snow Leopard).</p>

<p>Will we see a change in computer architecture for Apple hardware tomorrow (for computers and tablets alike)? or will they move their IPad to Intel hardware? They could also choose to wait 6 more months to release a very polished user experience.</p>

<p>We will see at 10:00 AM Pacific!</p>

<p>PS: The conference is over, now it is time let you know <a href="/blog/thoughts-on-wwdc-mmxiii/">what I think about it</a></p>

<p><em>Image by ©2013 Apple Inc.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Access Memories and Nonsensical Metada]]></title>
    <link href="http://disrupts.github.io/random-access-memories-and-nonsensical-metada/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-25T12:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://disrupts.github.io/random-access-memories-and-nonsensical-metada</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve just lost<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> a full post.
yeap, just finished writing it in gvim, hadn’t saved it nor copied it to wordpress online editor and saw miself forced to reboot my computer because.. I ran out of RAM.  I couldn’t switch programs, nor input anything. It was frozen. And it had plenty of space to use for swap (Mac OS X uses a swap file by default) but somehow it couldn’t handle it.</p>

<p>So what was it about?</p>

<p>Some weirdness I was confronted after ripping the new Daft Punk CD (I couldn’t resist, I bought it the same 21st of May it was launched).</p>

<p>The problem came from some alac rips (it did not happened with flac).</p>

<p>The files showed some strange creation dates when opened with <a href="https://mplayerhq.hu/design7/news.html">MPlayer</a>. Some ordered dates starting in the 20′s and ending in the 80′s.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/assets/images/2013-05-25-random-access-memories-and-nonsensical-metada/005.jpg" width="600" title="MPlayer screenshot including some strange metadata" ></p>

<p>At first I though it was some easter egg but after ripping the files a second time I realised those new files showed some similar dates, but not the same. That’s why I blamed XLD (the program I used to transcode from aiff to alac) but that was another mistake. XLD did a great job in finding metadata in a few seconds and ripping the whole album in under 5 min. I ended up blaming MPlayer, because no other player showed that metadata. THey all showed only ’2013′ as the date (which was also showed in a different line by MPlayer, as shown in the screenshot). Even the OS showed a real creation date which is, as expected, the day the files were created by XLD.</p>

<p>What do you think makes MPlayer show those dates consistently every time I play the songs?</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>sorry Apple, your Darwin kernel behaved properly. It was Firefox (from my beloved <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla</a>) which was responsible for the soft-crash. I have it setup to ask me if I want to accept cookies on every new website I visit and somehow one of them broke the app (oddly enough, I was, for once, running the release channel Firefox (stable) instead of <a href="http://nightly.mozilla.org/">Nightly</a> (daily build). That won’t change my mind about the browser and might soon sign up to collaborate with the developers (I came back to Firefox, after having switched to chrome almost at its debut, for <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mission/">philosophical</a> reasons, 2 years ago).<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
